<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Career on taihen.org / 418 ... engineering in progress</title><link>https://taihen.org/tags/career/</link><description>Recent content in Career on taihen.org / 418 ... engineering in progress</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taihen.org/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>We Got Tricked Into Writing Documentation</title><link>https://taihen.org/posts/we_got_tricked_into_writing_documentation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://taihen.org/posts/we_got_tricked_into_writing_documentation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t sign up to be a project manager. I got into programming because I loved the exploration, making mistakes, finding solutions and moving slowly bit by bit. One day I needed system tool then I wrote some C, the other time I needed some glue code, so I got comfortable with Perl or Bash. Needed to created website? Well&amp;hellip; PHP was the languge for it - basically whatever was up to the job. I never learned any of these to the level of a professional, was never interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed solving puzzles, one at the time, it was creative freeform craft. It was messy, it was dounting. It was fun, sooo much fun!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I spend my days writing prose about code instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://kentbeck.com/"&gt;Kent Beck&lt;/a&gt; calls AI code agents the genie in the bottle: &lt;strong&gt;you get what you wish for, not what you want&lt;/strong&gt;. He&amp;rsquo;s right, but in ways I did not expected.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Almost Right - but Wrong</title><link>https://taihen.org/posts/almost-right-but-wrong/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 21:55:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://taihen.org/posts/almost-right-but-wrong/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I care deeply about is &lt;strong&gt;helping other engineers grow&lt;/strong&gt;. Over the last year, I’ve had a lot of conversations, some with folks just entering the field, others with seasoned pros, asking the same question: &lt;strong&gt;how is AI going to reshape our work?&lt;/strong&gt; There is fear and uncertainty, but also some optimism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="theres-a-rhythm-to-these-tech-cycles"&gt;There’s a rhythm to these tech cycles.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen it before, big promises, huge hype, sweeping predictions. Right now, we’re being told that &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jackkelly/2025/04/25/the-jobs-that-will-fall-first-as-ai-takes-over-the-workplace/"&gt;AI will replace&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.techspot.com/news/108792-openai-ceo-sam-altman-warns-ai-could-wipe.html"&gt;entire roles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://gizmodo.com/ai-will-replace-recruiters-and-assistants-in-six-months-says-ceo-behind-chatgpt-rival-2000631871"&gt;maybe entire industries&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the same energy &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/autos/millions-professional-drivers-will-be-replaced-self-driving-vehicles-n817356"&gt;we saw&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/sanfrancisco/news/how-ubers-autonomous-cars-will-destroy-10-million-jobs-and-reshape-the-economy-by-2025-lyft-google-zack-kanter/"&gt;self-driving cars&lt;/a&gt;. For years, we were told they were just around the corner. But today, in 2025, I still don’t see a 40-ton truck rolling down the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Autobahn"&gt;Autobahn&lt;/a&gt; without a driver. Waymo works, yes, but in tightly controlled areas, in a few cities. Meanwhile, here in Europe, truck drivers are still &lt;a href="https://www.iru.org/news-resources/newsroom/half-european-truck-operators-cant-expand-due-driver-shortages"&gt;very much in demand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>