<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on taihen.org / 418 ... engineering in progress</title><link>https://taihen.org/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on taihen.org / 418 ... engineering in progress</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:15:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taihen.org/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MCP RIPEstat: Ask Your Network Questions in Plain English</title><link>https://taihen.org/posts/mcp-ripestat-announcement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 17:15:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://taihen.org/posts/mcp-ripestat-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever found yourself knee-deep in a routing incident at 3 AM, frantically switching between terminals and browser tabs trying to piece together BGP data? &lt;strong>I&amp;rsquo;ve been there&lt;/strong>. You&amp;rsquo;re chasing down a routing anomaly, your coffee&amp;rsquo;s gone cold, and you&amp;rsquo;re clicking through endless forms just to figure out which AS is announcing that suspicious prefix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What if I told you that instead of switching between terminals and browser tabs, you could use natural language to describe the problem, and then ask the computer to do the work for you?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accel-PPP Prometheus Exporter</title><link>https://taihen.org/posts/accel-exporter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://taihen.org/posts/accel-exporter/</guid><description>&lt;p>As infrastructure engineers, we often find ourselves bridging gaps between the tools we use and the monitoring systems we rely on. When I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated to &lt;strong>Prometheus&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Grafana&lt;/strong> on one of the sites, integrating &lt;a href="https://github.com/accel-ppp/accel-ppp">&lt;strong>Accel-PPP&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> posed a unique challenge. The absence of native Prometheus support for Accel-PPP meant I was stuck with an SNMP-based monitoring setup, but relying on SNMP for metrics felt like patching a modern system with legacy tools—inefficient and less than ideal. Additionally Accel-PPP &lt;a href="https://docs.accel-ppp.org/guides/control_features.html">lacks&lt;/a> any API or interface to get information about its state. This led me to develop &lt;a href="https://github.com/taihen/accel-exporter">&lt;strong>accel-exporter&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>