<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Unix on taihen.org / 418 ... engineering in progress</title><link>https://taihen.org/tags/unix/</link><description>Recent content in Unix on taihen.org / 418 ... engineering in progress</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://taihen.org/tags/unix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing dotfiles with GNU Stow</title><link>https://taihen.org/posts/stow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 22:36:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://taihen.org/posts/stow/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In Unix-like operating systems, dotfile is synonymous with hidden file. Usually used by programs to store configuration variables.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I have multiple machines, which I regularly work on. I keep sync of a set of personalized dotfiles between them – customized settings for programs that I’m using, like many of you. Till now, I was using my private git repository for things like my private scripts, &lt;a href="http://www.mutt.org/" title="Mutt E-Mail Client">Mutt&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.irssi.org/" title="Irssi IRC Client">Irssi&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://ekg2.org/" title="Ekg2 Multichat Client">Ekg2&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://tmux.sourceforge.net/" title="Tmux Terminal Multiplexer">Tmux&lt;/a> configurations. On the other hand some I keep publicly available for others i.e. on &lt;a href="https://github.com/taihen" title="GitHub Taihen">GitHub&lt;/a> like &lt;a href="https://github.com/taihen/vimfiles">Vim configs&lt;/a>. And oh boy, there are so many of them! The true is, I customize almost everything that I’m using including simple tools like cp (just to get progress bar or interactivity).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>January 1, 1970</title><link>https://taihen.org/posts/1970/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 22:36:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://taihen.org/posts/1970/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the day of my birthday, I wondered (of course - as many us do), if this is my start date, what is the to origin story of the birth date of computer time?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Unix epoch, defined as 00:00:00 UTC on January 1, 1970, serves as the foundational reference point for timekeeping in nearly all modern computing systems. This date, though seemingly arbitrary, emerged from a confluence of technical constraints, historical decisions, and practical considerations during Unix&amp;rsquo;s early development.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>